<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Meyke</title>
    <link>https://meykebos.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Meyke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://meykebos.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customer Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://meykebos.github.io/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meykebos.github.io/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>As our final assignment for the Techionista Academy, we had to create a Power BI report to analyse the customer sentiment for a Dutch company. Unfortunately, we have been asked to be careful with the data we share since it contains privacy sensitive information. Therefore, I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to share my code or the Power BI report itself. Instead, I will share screenshots of the result.
The data that was provided consisted of the following columns:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict House Prices</title>
      <link>https://meykebos.github.io/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meykebos.github.io/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The goal of the Kaggle House Prices Prediction contest is to predict the final price for each home in Ames, Iowa (United States). The contest provides 79 variables for each home, making it a challenge to be creative and selective with feature engineering.
I submitted 7 predictions to Kaggle. My higest score was 0.12881, good for a 2380 place on the leadership board with a total of 8972 teams.
  In order to be able to build a lineair regression model to predict the house prices, I first cleaned the data and imputed missing values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titanic</title>
      <link>https://meykebos.github.io/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meykebos.github.io/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The Kaggle Titanic competition is one of the most well known machine learning competitions out there. The goal is to predict the fate of the passengers onboard of the Titanic. Did they survive the 1912 disaster?
The Titanic competition was the first machine learning competition I participated in. After several submissions, I finally reached a top 6% score (place 1820 out of 33866 enrolled teams) with a Kaggle accuracy rate of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
